theanalysisfactor.com 2019-11-29

# Our Privacy Policy - The Analysis Factor

## Client Privacy

The privacy of our clients is of the utmost importance.  As a matter of standard procedure, we do not discuss clients’ names with others.  We treat all communications with our clients as confidential and will not share those communications with anyone.  We will never sell your information or provide any information about you, including your email address, to a third party.

Occasionally, prospective clients ask for references as a condition of retaining our service. Clients are not used as a source of reference without their prior approval.

## Information Collected

At The Analysis Factor, we collect the following information for the purpose of client engagement:

#### **Name and Contact Details**

**How We Collect This:** This information is collected if you fill out a form on our website and/or send us an email with the specific request and information to update your contact record. We will not collect any contact details without your consent.

**Why:**  We use your name and contact details to send you email messages. If you are a part of our membership program, we may use your address to mail you holiday cards and welcome items. Overall, your name and contact details are used to tailor our services to you and to enhance our customer service experience.

#### Payment Information

**How We Collect This:** We can only collect payment information if you provide it on an order form for a specific service. For credit card purchases, we can only view the type of card you used, the last 4 digits, and the expiration date.

**Why:** We use your payment information to receive the payment for the service you are requesting.

#### **Contact History**

**How We Collect This:**   If you are a part of our mailing list, we use Ontraport to send our email messages and to keep a history log of purchases, messages sent, messages opened, messages received, pages visited, buttons clicked, and forms filled. This information varies per user according to their level of interaction with our website and emails, and can expand to contain responses to surveys.

For more information about Ontraport and its compliance with GDPR policy, please visit [https://ontraport.com/legal#op-container–33/](https://ontraport.com/legal#op-container--33/).

**Why:**  We collect contact history to improve our customer service experience.

All information is held for as long as a contact is opted-in to our mailing list. To manage your opt-in status, look for the “Manage Your Subscription” link at the bottom of every email message we send you, or you can email us at _support@theanalysisfactor.com_.

## Your Rights

EU citizens have the following rights in regards to their personal data and privacy:

  * **Right of access** – You can request to see the information that The Analysis Factor has stored about you.
  * **Right to  ** **re-certification**  – You can request for your information to be updated.
  * **Right to erasure** – You can request the removal or deletion of your personal information (unless personal information is used to comply with legal obligation).
  * **Right to restrict processing** – You can restrict processing of your personal information if it is not being stored accurately or by objecting to the processing.
  * **Right to information portability** – You can request your personal information to be sent to another Data Controller that is not The Analysis Factor.

## Cookies

The Analysis Factor uses Site Analytics and Site Functionality cookies on our website.

Site analytics cookies allow us to analyze and measure how users are interacting with our site. Site functionality cookies allow us to make site navigation easier. If you are a returning user, site functionality cookies allow us to give you direct access to items you already opted in for.

By using our site, you are agreeing to placing Site Analytics and Site functionality cookies on your device and having access to these when you visit TheAnalysisFactor.com (or our other public-facing websites, like TheCraftofStatisticalAnalysis.com) in the future.

## Research Data and Personal Information Confidentiality

We agree to keep all research data and documents associated with your project and personal information confidential.  In regards to your research, we will not share the materials to which we have access, or the ideas, opinions and information they contain, with any other person outside our team unless we have express permission from the client to do so.  As part of this agreement, we will not independently publish research data or analyses stemming from this work without the involvement and/or permission of the client.  We agree to return all research data and files associated with this project upon the request of the client, and to ensure that no files remain on our system after that time. We will not share your personal information with any other person outside our team unless we have permission from the client to do so.

## Information Security

The Analysis Factor understands and recognizes the importance of research data and personal information to its business operations and hence is committed to providing its customers a secure information processing environment. The Analysis Factor will ensure the privacy of customer research data and personal information by protecting it against unauthorized access, disclosure and/or loss. We will adhere to modern security procedures that prohibit unauthorized access, disclosure, duplication, modification, diversion, destruction, loss, misuse, or theft of customer information.

Information security measures will be reviewed once a year–or earlier if circumstances require–to ensure policy compliance.

## How to Contact Us

We are always happy to hear from our users and customers. If you have any questions, feedback about our policy, or want to exercise any of your rights listed above, please [use our contact form](https://www.theanalysisfactor.com/contact-us/), or email us  at _support@theanalysisfactor.com_.

**Mailing Address:**  
The Analysis Factor, LLC  
430 W State St, Suite #204, Ithaca, NY 14850
